Guide to the Tara Rodgers Pink Noises Riot Grrrl Collection MSS.456
Fales Library and Special Collections
Tara Rodgers Pink Noises Riot Grrrl Collection
1976-2015
Fales Library and Special Collections
Rodgers, Tara, 1973-
MSS.456
4 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, 1 tall half manuscript box, 1 small flat box and 1 oversized folder in shared housing.
Tara Rodgers (1973-) (also known by her stage name Analog Tara) is a Washington DC based composer, historian and critic of electronic music. She is best known as the founder of Pinknoises.com, as well as her work as an academic and voice for women in the electronic music industry. The Tara Rodgers Pink Noises Riot Grrrl Collection features music and writing produced by or collected by Tara Rodgers related to her personal practice (including critiques, articles, and audio recordings), role in academia (essays, syllabi, event flyers), work at Pinknoises.com, and interest in the feminist electronic music scene (collection of magazines and zines, audio recordings).
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Scope and Contents
The Tara Rodgers Pink Noises Riot Grrrl Collection, dated 1976-2015, consists of materials created, produced, and collected by Tara Rodgers documenting her involvement in academia, critical theory, and the music industry. The collection includes correspondence, audio recordings under the name Audio Tara, audio recordings by female electronic and experimental musicians, and publications concerning feminist interests both inside and outside the music industry, including Bust, Bitch,Groove, and XLR8R and a collection of comic books featuring female superheroes (Wonder Woman, She-Hulk, Super Girl, Spider Woman). The collection also includes original writings by Rodgers, including magazine articles and academic publications, as well as other materials documenting her academic activities, such as syllabi, event programs, and program notes from educational institutions she has taught at or worked for.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Tara Rodgers, June 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.028.
Biographical Note
Tara Rodgers (1973-) (also known by her stage name Analog Tara) is a Washington DC based composer, historian and critic of electronic music. She is best known as the founder of Pinknoises.com, a website dedicated to documenting the work of women in the electronic music industry and providing music production resources. Rodgers also authored the book, Pink Noises: Women On Electronic Music And Sound, a collection of interviews featuring female professionals in the electronic music industry. Rodgers has a AB in American Studies from Brown University, an MFA in Electronic Music and Recording Media from Mills College and a PhD in Communication Studies from McGill University. She has been visiting faculty at the School of the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, an assistant professor of Women's studies and Distinguished Faculty Fellow in Digital Cultures and Creativity at the University of Maryland and a faculty member at Dartmouth College.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Comic books.; Electronic music.; Musical criticism.; Electronic music -- History and criticism; Women musicians -- United States.; Feminism and music; Musicians -- United States
- Writing, 2007-2015 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Writing: Pinknoises.com, circa 2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Articles and Book Chapters, 2006-2015 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- PhD Dissertation, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- MFA Thesis, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- AB Thesis, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Interviews, 2001-2012 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Pink Noises Book Reviews, 2010-2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Reviews and Press, 2000-2014 (Box 1, Folder 11-14)
- Tara/Pink Noises Files, 2001-2008 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Analog Tara/ Tara Rodgers/ Pink Noises Programs, 2002-2013 (Box 1, Folder 16-19)
- Studio Notes, 1999-2012 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Butterfly Effects (2006): Score (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Programs, etc: Mills/ MFA, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- The Women Studies Multimedia Studio, University of Maryland, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Photographs, 2001-2003 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- CV, 1995-2016 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence: Other, 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Syllabi, 2005-2013 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Correspondence: Pinknoises.com, 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Pink Noises Book: Promo Materials, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Newspaper and Web Clippings, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Flyers, 2001-2006 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Berklee College of Music Music Production Workshop Binder, 1998 (Box 1)
- Music Production Notes Binder, 1997-2000 (Box 1)
- Music and Electronic Arts Magazines: XLR8R, 2000-2004 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
- Music and Electronic Arts Magazines, 2001-2009 (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
- Music and Electronic Arts Magazines: Tape Op, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Music and Electronic Arts Magazines: Foarm Magazine, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Music and Electronic Arts Magazines: Grooves, 2000-2004 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
- Feminist Zines and Magazines, 1996-2002 (Box 2, Folder 15-18)
- Feminst Zines and Magazines: Venus, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Feminist Zines and Magazines: Bust, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Feminist Zines and Magazines: Bitch, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Women in Comic Books, 1976-1984 (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
- Other Ephemera, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Issues of XLR8R, 2000-2004 (Box 3)
- Analog Tara CD/ Pink Noises Art, 2000-2002; cuid5830 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Analog Tara Demo Tapes, 1996 (Box 6)
- CDs and LPs by Women in Electronic and Experimental Music (Analog Tara and Others), 1998-2015 (Box 4, Box 6)
- Women Take Back the Noise Promotional Pack, 2006 (Box 6)
- Photographs, 2000 (Box 7)
- Event Posters, 2011-2012 (Box Shared Fales Accessions 007, Folder 1)
- Vinyl Records, 1999-2014 (Box 5)